♪ IT IS ALMOST 1:00 P.M. IN
SYDNEY AND 11:00 A.M. IN HONG KONG.
I AM PAUL ALLEN. ASIAN STOCKS ADVANCE AS UPBEAT
U.S. GROWTH DATA BACK THE CASE FOR A SOFT LANDING.
INFLATION IN TOKYO GAIN SPACE, PUTTING A POTENTIAL BOJ RATE
HIKE THIS YEAR BACK ON THE TABLE.
KAMALA HARRIS DEFENSE POLICY BACKFLIPS IN HER FIRST INTERVIEW
AS DEMOCRATIC NOMINEE. A BLOOMBERG POLL SHOWS SHE IS
SUSTAINING MOMENTUM IN BATTLEGROUND STATES.
I'M BONNIE PROMISES -- AMBANI PROMISES RAPID GROWTH IN CLEAN
ENERGY AND AI. AVRIL HONG IS IN SINGAPORE.
MARKETS HAVE THAT FRIDAY FEELING.
WE ARE SEEING THEM ENDING THE WEEK AND THE MONTH AND A PRETTY
GOOD MOOD AS THE GAUGE OF STOCKS IN THE REGION SURGING.
WE ARE SEEING THE STOCKS IN CHINA LEADING THE WAY.
SOME OF THE EARNINGS HAVE BEEN COMING IN ARE LOOKING PRETTY
SOLID BUT WE ALSO HAVE THE IDEA THAT AT LEAST THE GOVERNMENT OF
THE U.S. AND CHINA APPEARED TO BE TALKING SO MAYBE A BIT OF
LIFT IN SENTIMENT IN THAT REGARD.
THE NARRATIVE IS HOW THE U.S. ECONOMY GETTING THAT GDP REVISED
HIGHER THANKS TO RESILIENT CONSUMPTION PICTURE, THAT IS
REALLY WHAT STOCKS IN THE U.S. OVERNIGHT WERE RUNNING WITH,
DESPITE THIS CONCERN RELATED TO THE AI, THE FROTHY VALUATIONS
AND MAYBE NVIDIA NOT LIVING UP TO ALL THOSE EXPECTATIONS.
SOME GAINS IN JAPAN AS WELL TODAY ALSO ON THE DATA FRONT.
WE GOT TOKYO CORE CPI NUMBERS HOTTER THAN EXPECTED.
IF YOU TAKE A LOOK AT THE JAPANESE CURRENCY, IT IS PRETTY
MUCH WHERE WE SAW IT THIS TIME YESTERDAY.
WE ARE ALSO SEEING THE YIELD DIFFERENTIALS NARROWING BETWEEN
THE U.S. AND CHINA CERTAINLY. OFFSHORE YEN SITTING WELL BELOW
THE 7.09 LEVEL. TAKING A QUICK LOOK AT U.S.
FUTURES AS WELL AS WE SAW A MIXED CLOSE OVERNIGHT ON WALL
STREET. IF YOU CAN TAKE A LOOK AT THIS
BOARD, IT WILL SHOW YOU HOW THE NASDAQ FUTURES ALONG WITH THE
S&P 500 FUTURES ARE FARING. OF COURSE, IT WAS NVIDIA THAT
REALLY SLID ABOUT 6% OVERNIGHT, MAY BE RECOUPING A BIT OF THOSE
LOSSES WHEN TRADING REOPENS AGAIN.
LET'S GET MORE ON MARKETS WITH OUR PARTNER AT JAVELIN WEALTH
MANAGEMENT AND BLOOMBERG MLIV EXECUTIVE EDITOR MARK CUDMORE.
MARK, LET'S START WITH YOU. YOU HAVE A VERY BULLISH CASE FOR
EQUITIES. DO YOU SEE ANY REASON TO SEE
THAT DERAILED IN A WAY. MARK: NO.
EVERYTHING IS AWESOME. I CAN LITERALLY NOT SEE ANY
OBVIOUS MAJOR BEARISH FACTOR. THE FED IS DESPERATE TO EASE,
GIVEN HALF A CHANCE. THE ECONOMY IS DOING
BRILLIANTLY, THE CONSUMER IS BOOMING.
ENERGY PRICES ARE AT THE BOTTOM OF THE RANGES, INFLATION IS
COMING DOWN, JOBS MARKET IS STILL GROWING, MAYBE AT A SLOWER
PACE BUT STILL GROWING. EARNINGS ARE SOLID, DOLLAR IS
SOFTENING AT THE MARGIN. IT IS A RARE TIME THAT I'VE BEEN
OVER 20 YEARS AND MARKETS, IT IS RARE MOMENTS WHEN YOU GET EVERY
SINGLE MAJOR INPUT, YOU GO BULLISH, BULLISH, BULLISH,
BULLISH. THE ONLY THING I CAN KIND OF
THINK OF IS VALUATIONS ARE A LITTLE BIT EXPENSIVE BUT NOT
MORE EXPENSIVE THAN THEY'VE BEEN BEFORE.
THEY ARE NOT. ELECTION, YEAH.
PEOPLE TALK ABOUT STRONG JOB SPRINT NEXT WEEK, YIELDS WILL GO
HIGHER. YIELDS GOING HIGHER BECAUSE THE
ECONOMY IS TOO STRONG FOR RATE CUTS IS A POSITIVE FOR STOCKS.
IT MEANS IT'S GOOD FOR THE ECONOMY, THE CONSUMER, GOOD FOR
EARNINGS. STOCKMARKETS GENERALLY, IT'S A
BULLISH ENVIRONMENT OUT THERE. TICKS ALL THE RIGHT BOXES.
DO YOU AGREE WITH THAT? HOW MUCH FURTHER ROOFER UPSIDE
DO THINK THERE IS? I DO THINK THERE IS FURTHER
ROOFER UPSIDE. NUMBERS SURPRISED ON THE UPSIDE
-- FURTHER ROOM FOR UPSIDE. NUMBERS SURPRISED ON THE UPSIDE.
WE HAD A LONG, SOLID RUN TILL NOW IN THE YEAR, AND THERE WILL
BE INVESTORS THAT WILL BE THINKING I CAN PROBABLY TAKE
SOME MONEY OFF THE TABLE NOW. WATCH OUT FOR THE VOLATILITY
THAT'S COMING THROUGH TO THE END OF THE YEAR.
I DON'T SEE MUCH DOWNSIDE FROM HERE.
IT WILL BE A BIT MORE RANGE BOUND, PROBABLY NOT AS
OPTIMISTIC AS MARK. BUT THERE'S UPSIDE, THERE'S LESS
RISK TO EQUITIES AT THIS POINT. AS MUCH AS I HATE TO RAIN ON
MARK'S PARADE, LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT SOME AREAS OF THE MARKET THAT
COULD BE A BIT SLUGGISH GOING FORWARD.
EXHIBIT A, BIG TECH. WE HAVE THE MAGNIFICENT SEVEN
AFTER BEING MAGNIFICENT NOW LAGGING THE BROADER INDEX.
HOW MUCH MOMENTUM DO YOU FEEL THERE IS IN THIS SPACE?
IS IT A BUY? WE ARE STILL BULLISH ON
TECHNOLOGY SO I AM IN MARK'S CAMP ON THAT.
WE DO FEEL THERE WILL BE A BIT OF NORMALIZATION IN THE
EXPECTATION OF TECHNOLOGY. THIS WEEK WAS ALL ABOUT NVIDIA,
RIGHT? IT FEELS LIKE IT'S RELATIONSHIP
WITH INVESTORS IS A BIT LIKE A CHILD WITH DEMANDING PARENTS.
YOU GOT 99 IN MATH, WHY DID YOU NOT GET 100?
YOU GOT 100 IN MATH BUT YOU ARE IN YOUR SWING TRIAL, SO IT'S
NEVER ENOUGH -- SWIMMING TRIAL SO IT'S NEVER ENOUGH.
INVESTOR EXPECTATION IS ASTRONOMICALLY HIGH.
WE ARE STILL IN THE INFRASTRUCTURE DEVELOPMENT PHASE
OF AI AND THE APPLICATION PHASE IS GOING TO BE A BIT MORE LONG
DRAWN, AND INVESTORS MAY BE DON'T HAVE THE PATIENCE FOR
THAT. THAT'S NOT NECESSARILY BAD
BECAUSE IT TAKES A BIT OF THE FOCUS AWAY FROM TECH AND ALLOWS
IT TO BUILD AT A MORE NORMAL PACE, WHICH WE EXPECT TO HAPPEN.
I WANT TO JUMP IN HERE. PAUL, I CANNOT BELIEVE YOU
REIGNED ON MY PARADE. HE OPENED A BATTLE.
IT'S SHAMEFUL THAT BLOOMBERG MAGNIFICENT SEVEN TECH INDEX
TOTAL RETURN YEAR TO DATE IS ONLY 33.5%.
IT'S DOING TERRIBLY. I WOULD BE REALLY UPSET WITH
EIGHT ALREADY 3.5% GAIN AFTER EIGHT MONTH SEVERE.
IT'S -- WITH A 33.5% GAME AFTER EIGHT MONTHS IN THE YEAR.
IT'S BEEN A GREAT YEAR. WE JUST TALKED ABOUT EVEN PAUL'S
LAGGING TECH INDEX, WHICH HAS ONLY RETURNED 33%, MAY BE SOME
PEOPLE MIGHT WANT TO TAKE SOME PROFIT.
I SEE IT. I KIND OF SEE THAT AS THE PATH,
I THINK IT WILL BE A BIT MORE ROCKY THAN THE STRAIGHT-LINE WE
HAVE SEEN BUT I THINK THE PEOPLE WILL ULTIMATELY BE FORCED INTO
THE MARKET AGAIN AS THEY GO THE MARKET KEEPS ON CLIMBING THE
WALL OF WORRY. DO YOU NOT SEE THAT NARRATIVE?
ABSOLUTELY. WHAT THAT WILL RESULT IN IS A
BIT OF ROTATION AS WELL. WE SEE MORE COMING INTO EMERGING
MARKETS IN ASIA NOW WITH THE RATE CUTS PRETTY MUCH PRICED IN
FOR SEPTEMBER AND MAYBE ANOTHER ONE LATER IN THE YEAR.
IT WILL BE A RISK ON ENVIRONMENT.
WE WILL SEE MORE COMING. WHETHER IT IS INDIA, ASIA,
WHETHER IT IS EMERGING MARKETS, THOSE ARE BENEFICIARIES.
WE WILL SEE MORE ROTATION. PROBABLY WE WILL SEE MORE MONEY
COMING INTO JAPAN BECAUSE U.S. RATE CUTS ARE DOING BOJ'S JOB
FOR BOJ IN THE PATH TO NORMALIZATION.
IT MAY NOT JUST BE A TECH RALLY, IT MAY NOT BE A U.S. RALLY.
WE HAVE BEEN OVERWEIGHT ON TECHNOLOGY, THAT'S WORKED VERY
WELL FOR US. CYCLICALS WILL COME THROUGH.
I THINK INVESTORS ARE MORE PREEMPTIVE NOW THAN REACTIVE TO
WHAT HAPPENS IN THE MARKET. WE WILL SEE INTEREST IN THE
SMALL-CAP SECTOR. MY WORRY OVER THERE IS THAT AS
WE SEE THE ROTATION INTO THESE SECTORS, WE ARE STILL IN A HIGH
INTEREST-RATE ENVIRONMENT. AND IT WILL TAKE SOME TIME FOR
THE INTEREST RATE CUTS TO FLOW-THROUGH INTO THE FINANCIALS
OF THESE COMPANIES. WHAT WE SAW WITH TECH STOCKS,
EXPECTATIONS ARE SKYHIGH, THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT COULD HAPPEN IN
THESE SMALL OR EVEN CYCLICALS. THE MARKETS WILL EXPECT RETURNS
TO COME THROUGH MUCH FASTER THAN IT DOES.
COME NEXT EARNINGS CYCLE, ONCE SMALL CAPS DO NOT GIVE
EXTRAORDINARY RETURNS. REMEMBER, THERE WAS ACTUALLY A
RATING DOWNWARDS IN THE RUSSELL INDEX.
IF THAT DOES NOT HAPPEN, WE WILL PROBABLY SEE ANOTHER BOUT OF
VOLATILITY IN THESE STOCKS. DIVERGENT VIEWS.
I LOVE IT, A BIT OF DRAMA. I WANTED TO POST TO YOU THE MLIV
QUESTION OF THE DAY. IN TERMS OF RETURNS NEXT MONTH,
EQUITIES VERSUS U.S. INVESTMENT BONDS AND TREASURIES, WHERE DO
YOU SEE THE RETURNS? DO YOU THINK EQUITIES WOULD DO
BETTER THAN BONDS? IT'S A VERY INTERESTING MONTH
TO BE POSING THAT QUESTION. IF YOU LOOK AT IT, THE AVERAGE
THREE YEAR CORRELATION BETWEEN MIDTERM U.S. COMMON BONDS AND
EQUITIES IS AT THIS POINT AT ITS HIGHEST SINCE THE 1990'S, SO
IT'S MUCH HARDER TO SELECT AN ASSET CLASS RIGHT NOW.
BOTH ARE FAIRLY PRICED IN AT THIS POINT.
WE WILL SEE MORE ISSUANCES COMING THROUGH IN SEPTEMBER SO
THEY'LL PROBABLY PUT A BIT MORE PRESSURE ON FIXED-INCOME.
I AM A LITTLE BIT LEANING MORE TOWARDS EQUITIES BUT EQUITY
REACTION OF THE MARKET IS A LOT MORE SENTIMENTAL AT
THIS POINT. WE WILL SEE ANOTHER LITTLE BOUT
OF VOLATILITY. BUT OVERALL, YES, I THINK IT IS
STILL MORE POSITIVE FOR EQUITIES AND FIXED INCOME.
MARK: I GOT A QUESTION. I AGREE WITH ALMOST EVERYTHING
SHE HAS SAID, I NOT HAVE BEEN DIFFICULT TODAY.
I AM NOT DISAGREEING. SHE IS TALKING SINCE, I AGREE.
THE BIT I AM CURIOUS ABOUT IS YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT JAPAN AS
BEING ONE OF YOUR FAVORITE SECTORS.
TO ME, THE JAPAN STORY HAS BEEN VERY MUCH ABOUT THE YEN
DEPRECIATION. IF YOU LOOK AT HOW JAPANESE
STOCKS HAVE DONE IN DOLLAR TERMS, THEY HAVE NOT BEEN A
GREAT STORY. IT'S BEEN IN YEN TERMS
THEY'VE BEEN A GREAT STORY. IF YOU THINK JAPAN IT CAN BE
OUTPERFORM IS AGAIN, DO THINK AGAIN DEPRECIATION TRADE CAN
RESTART? OR DO YOU THINK THEY CAN
GENUINELY OUTPERFORM AND EVEN DOLLAR TERMS -- IN EVEN DOLLAR
TERMS? I THINK THEY CAN GENUINELY
OUTPERFORM IN DOLLAR TERMS. STRENGTHENING YEN IS GOING TO BE
NEGATIVE FOR EQUITIES BUT THE FUNDAMENTAL STORY IS VERY STRONG
IN JAPAN. CORPORATE RESTRUCTURING IS IN
PLACE. WE ARE SEEING THE RESULTS OF
THAT. WE ARE SEEING SHAREHOLDER
RETURNS INCREASING NOW. JUST TO GIVE YOU AN INTERESTING
DATA POINT, WE ARE LOOKING AT EARNINGS REVISION NUMBERS, ACWI
AVERAGE FOR THE LAST 12 MONTHS IS LESS THAN 8%, WHEREAS FOR
INDIA AND JAPAN, IT HAS BEEN MORE THAN 18%.
IT IS 18% TO 20% RANGE SO THERE'S A LOT MORE VALUE TO BE
UNLOCKED IN THESE MARKETS, EVEN THOUGH THEY DO LOOK PRICEY,
ESPECIALLY INDIA AND JAPAN. A LITTLE BIT CURRENCY WILL
REMAIN A CONCERN. THE FUNDAMENTAL EQUITY STORY IN
JAPAN IS QUITE STRONG. PAUL: ALL RIGHT.
MARK, I'VE GOT TO TELL YOU, DON'T TAKE IT PERSONALLY, DON'T
TRY TO PICK A FIGHT. WHEREVER I SEE LIGHT, I NEED TO
BRING DARK, IT'S JUST ME. ONE MORE QUESTION BEFORE WE GO
THAT I THINK WE CAN ALL AGREE ON.
I THINK THE PATH OF LEAST RESISTANCE FOR THE U.S. DOLLAR
HERE IS PROBABLY WEAKER. DOES THAT LEAD YOU TO LOOK
AROUND SOME EMERGING MARKETS, PARTICULARLY IN ASIA?
YES, ABSOLUTELY. MARK: DON'T GIVE HIM AN EASY WIN
. ARGUE WITH HIM.
I AGREE WITH EVERYONE. MARK: NO FUN.
SORRY TO INTERRUPT. GO AHEAD.
WE ARE BULLISH ON EMERGING MARKETS AND I THINK DOLLAR
WEAKNESS IS GOING TO ALLOW THE EMERGING MARKETS TO CONTINUE OR
PROCEED WITH THE RATE CUTS THAT THEY HAVE BEEN HOLDING OFF FOR A
PRETTY LONG TIME NOW. THERE IS A STRONG GROWTH STORIES
IF YOU LOOK AT INDONESIA, IF YOU LOOK AT INDIA.
THERE ARE REFORMS IN MALAYSIA AS WELL.
IT'S BEEN THE CURRENCY RISK THAT THEY'VE ALL BEEN AVOIDING, SO I
THINK IT IS DEFINITELY A POSITIVE FOR RISK ASSETS AND
EMERGING MARKETS IN PARTICULAR, PAUL.
WE WILL LEAVE IT THERE FOR TODAY.
THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR COMING AND SHARING YOUR INSIGHTS WITH US.
GREAT TO HAVE YOU BOTH, POLKA ESPECIALLY.
MARK: I WILL TAKE IT. I DID NOT GET ONE.
JAVELIN WEALTH MANAGEMENT AND BLOOMBERG MLIV EXECUTIVE EDITOR
MARK CUDMORE. PAUL?
PAUL: LET'S GET TO SOME BREAKING NEWS OUT OF INTEL.
INTEL SAYS IT IS CONSIDERING SPLITTING OFF ITS FOUNDRY AND
SCRAPPING FACTORY PROJECTS AS WELL.
IT IS SAID TO BE EXPLORING OPTIONS WITH GOLDMAN AND MORGAN
STANLEY. INTEL UNDERSTOOD TO BE WORKING
WITH INVESTMENT BANKERS TO HELP IT NAVIGATE WHAT'S BEEN A PRETTY
DIFFICULT PERIOD IN ITS HISTORY. THESE REPORTS ACCORDING TO
PEOPLE FAMILIAR WITH THE MATTER DISCUSSING A NUMBER OF
SCENARIOS, BUT UNDERSTOOD TO INCLUDE SPINNING OFF THE FOUNDRY
BUSINESS AND SCRAPPING THOSE FACTORY PROJECTS AS WELL.
STILL MORE TO COME ON "BLOOMBERG MARKETS: ASIA."
WE ARE GOING TO PREVIEW INDIA'S GDP REPORT, IT COMES OUT LATER
ON FRIDAY. WE WILL BE JOINED TO DISCUSS WHY
THEY ARE EXPECTING SHARP SLOWDOWN IN THE SECOND COURT.
U.S. PRESIDENT -- VICE PRESIDENT KAMALA HARRIS VOWS TO PRIORITIZE
THE MIDDLE CLASS IF SHE IS ELECTED.
THAT'S UP NEXT. THIS IS BLOOMBERG.
♪
PAUL: U.S. DEMOCRATIC PRESIDENTIAL CANDIDATE KAMALA
HARRIS HAS GIVEN HER FIRST TV INTERVIEW SINCE HER NOMINATION
SPEAKING TO CNN. LET'S TAKE A LISTEN TO SOME OF
THE HIGHLIGHTS. MY AGENDA INCLUDES WHAT WE
NEED TO DO TO BRING DOWN THE PRICE OF GROCERIES, FOR EXAMPLE,
DEALING WITH AN ISSUE LIKE PRICE GOUGING.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO TO EXTEND THE CHILD TAX CREDIT TO HELP YOUNG
FAMILIES BE ABLE TO TAKE CARE OF THEIR CHILDREN AND THEIR MERCY
-- IN THEIR MOST FORMATIVE YEARS.
WHAT WE NEED TO DO TO BRING DOWN THE COST OF HOUSING.
I MADE THAT CLEAR ON THE DEBATE STAGE IN 2020 THAT I WOULD NOT
BEEN FRACKING AS VICE PRESIDENT -- BAN FRACKING.
AS VICE PRESIDENT, I DO NOT BEND FRACKING -- BAN FRACKING.
AS PRESIDENT, I WILL NOT BEEN FRACKING.
-- BAN FRACKING. I THINK IT WOULD BE TO THE
BENEFIT OF THE AMERICAN PUBLIC TO HAVE A MEMBER OF MY CABINET
WHO WAS A REPUBLICAN. WE HAVE TO GET A DEAL DONE.
THIS WARMEST END -- THIS WAR MUST AND.
AND WE MUST GET A DEAL THAT IS ABOUT GETTING THE HOSTAGES OUT.
I'VE MET WITH THE FAMILIES OF THE AMERICAN HOSTAGES.
LET'S GET THE HOSTAGES OUT. LET'S GET THE CEASE FIRE DONE.
PAUL: BLOOMBERG EDITOR DEREK WALLBANK JOINS US NOW WITH MORE.
, THE HEARSE FACING I GUESS -- KAMALA HARRIS FACING INEVITABLE
ACCUSATIONS THAT SHE'S FLIP FLOPPING, REVERSING ON EARLY
POLICY DECISIONS. HOW SHE EXPLAIN ALL THIS AWAY?
WELL, LOOK, PAUL, I THINK THIS IS KAMALA HARRIS' FIRST BIG
CHANCE AND SHE GOT THE -- SINCE SHE GOT THE DEMOCRATIC
PRESIDENTIAL NOMINATION TO SIT DOWN WITH A MAJOR MEDIA OUTLET
WHERE HER CAMPAIGN WAS NOT NECESSARILY THE ONE DRIVING
ISSUES AND IT WENT FINE. THE CNN REPORTER WHO DID THIS IS
A VERY, VERY GOOD CORRESPONDENT. SHE ASKED SOME TOUGH QUESTIONS.
AND HARRIS WAS READY FOR THEM I THINK.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T THINK YOU WILL SEE ANYTHING THAT'S A MAJOR SORT
OF GAFFE POINT OUT OF THIS. SHE AND TIM WALZ ADJUSTED THAT,
BUT ALSO PUT -- ADDRESSED THAT BUT ALSO PUT FORWARD THEIR VIEWS
OF CONTRAST, WHERE THEY THOUGHT THEY WERE PROBABLY IN A BETTER
POSITION TO TAKE THE COUNTRY FORWARD THAN A AND JD VANCE.
THIS IS WAS -- THIS WAS A MOMENT YOU SORT OF WATCH FOR.
WAS THERE A BIG TRIP UP THAT CHANGES THE DYNAMIC OF THE RACE?
NO, OK, ONTO THE NEXT THING. NO MAJOR TRIP UPS BUT YOU
WONDER IF THERE'S GOING TO BE ENOUGH TO SAY VALUES HAVEN'T
CHANGED. THEY HAVE TO IN A WAY DEFEND
SOME OF THESE SHIFTS IN POLICY STANCES ON THE WAR AND ON
FRACKING. BUT TO YOUR POINT, HOW MUCH
MOMENTUM DO YOU THINK KAMALA HAS UNTIL NOVEMBER?
I THINK IT'S A GREAT QUESTION.
A LOT OF THESE ISSUES HAVE REALLY LOCALIZED EFFECTS.
FRACKING YOU BRING UP IS A REALLY ACTING SMART WANT TO TALK
ABOUT BECAUSE IT IS CRITICAL IN THE STATE OF PENNSYLVANIA, WHERE
THERE IS A LOT OF NATURAL GAS AVAILABILITY.
WE JUST DID ANOTHER POLL, BLOOMBERG MORNING CONSULT PAUL
THAT FOUND KAMALA HARRIS HAS RISEN UP TO NOW A FOUR
PERCENTAGE POINT LEAD IN THE COMMONWEALTH OF PENNSYLVANIA,
POSSIBLY THE MOST CRITICAL SWING STATE.
ANSWERS LIKE THAT ARE GOING TO BE REALLY BIG FOR HER, AS AND
WHEN SHE AND DONALD TRUMP ARE PRESSED ON THE ISSUE OF NIPPON
STILL GOING AFTER U.S. STEEL. THAT'S BIG IN PITTSBURGH.
A LOT OF THINGS THINGS HAVE BOTH A NATIONAL AND LOCAL AUDIENCE.
IF I AM LOOKING AT THAT POLE, OVERALL, WE ARE FINDING KAMALA
HARRIS IN A NARROW LEAD ACROSS A LOT OF THESE SWING STATES, BUT I
A VERY DIFFERENT POSITION FROM WHERE JOE BIDEN WAS AGAINST
DONALD TRUMP. IF YOU LOOK AT IT, ACROSS ALL
THE SWING STATES, AGAIN, VERY NARROW LEADS IN SOME OF THESE
PLACES. IF YOU ARE TO PUT THIS ACROSS
THE ENTIRE ELECTORAL MAP IN THIS WERE TO HAPPEN ON ELECTION
NIGHT, KAMALA HARRIS WOULD WIN AND WITH ABOUT TWO STATES IN HER
RESERVE AS AN EDGE JUST IN CASE. SO A LONG WAY TO GO, A LONG WAY
TO GO. BUT IF YOU ARE HARRIS, YOU
PROBABLY LIKE WHERE YOU ARE COMING OUT OF THE CONVENTIONS
INTO THIS ONE ON ONE WITH TRUMP. NOW, ALL EYES ARE GOING TO BE
GOING ONTO THAT DEBATE THAT THEY HAVE TOGETHER.
OF COURSE, THE LAST DEBATE WAS A PRETTY CONSEQUENTIAL ONE, WAS IT
NOT? ALL RIGHT, THANK YOU SO MUCH
FOR SHARING YOUR INSIGHTS. WE STILL HAVE A LONG WAY TO GO.
AND AS WE'VE SEEN IN U.S. POLITICS, A LOT CAN CHANGE VERY
QUICKLY. BUT THANKS FOR SHARING YOUR
INSIGHTS WITH US. DEREK WALLBANK, BLOOMBERG
EDITOR. PAUL?
PAUL: LET'S GET TO SOME OF THE MORE, SOME OF THE OTHER TOP
GEOPOLITICAL STORIES WE ARE FOLLOWING.
BLOOMBERG HAS LEARNED THAT THE NETHERLANDS PLANS TO LIMIT
ASML'S ABILITY TO REPAIR AND MAINTAIN SEMI CONDUCTOR
EQUIPMENT FOR CHINESE CUSTOMERS. OURCES SAY THE DUTCH GOVERNMENT
WILL PROBABLY NOT RENEW SOME LICENSES TO SERVICE AND PROVIDE
SPARE PARTS IN CHINA THAT EXPIRE AT YEAR END.
WITHDRAWING MAINTENANCE SUPPORT COULD RENDER CHIPMAKING
EQUIPMENT INOPERABLE AS SOON AS NEXT YEAR.
NIPPON STEEL SAYS THE JAPANESE GOVERNMENT NEEDS TO IMPOSE AN
ANTIDUMPING TARIFF ON CHINESE EXPORTS TO PROTECT THE DOMESTIC
INDUSTRY. NIPPON SAYS THE FIRM IS LOBBING
THE GOVERNMENT ON THIS ISSUE ALONGSIDE OTHER STEELMAKERS.
IT SAYS OTHERS INCLUDING THE U.S., EUROPE, AND SOUTH KOREA
HAVE ALREADY DONE SO, LEAVING JAPAN VULNERABLE IF IT DOES NOT
FOLLOW. WE HAVE PLENTY MORE AHEAD.
THIS IS BLOOMBERG. ♪
♪ PAUL: AS WE MENTIONED A BIT
EARLIER, INTEL SAID TO BE EXPLORING OPTIONS TO COPE WITH
THIS HISTORIC SLUMP, ACCORDING TO BLOOMBERG SOURCES.
THE COMPANIES WORKING WITH INVESTMENT BANKERS TO HELP
NAVIGATE THE MOST DIFFICULT TIME IN ITS HISTORY.
ANNABELLE DROULERS IS HERE WITH THE DETAILS.
WHAT MORE DO WE KNOW? ANNABELLE: IT REALLY IS
INTERESTING TIMING FOR THIS BLOOMBERG SCOOP TO HAVE COME OUT
BECAUSE YOU THINK ABOUT THE CONTEXT AWARE INTEL IS.
WE HAD EARNINGS EARLIER THIS MONTH AND THEY WERE BLEAK.
WE SAW THE WORST SHARE DECLINE IN ABOUT 40 YEARS FOR THE
COMPANY. THEY GAVE A VERY GRIM GROWTH
FORECAST. THEY ALSO MADE OR ANNOUNCED
PLANS TO SLASH 15,000 JOBS. HOW IS INTEL GOING TO CHART HIS
PATH FORWARD? THE COMPANY IS HOLDING TALKS
WITH ITS REALLY LONG TIME BANKERS, SO THE LIKES OF GOLDMAN
SACHS, MORGAN STANLEY AND IT IS TRYING TO GET ADVICE ON, WHERE
DO THEY GO FROM HERE LOOKING AT THE DIFFERENT POSSIBILITIES?
ONE OF THOSE THAT IS THE MOST EXTREME SEEMS TO BE SPLITTING
OFF OR LISTING ITS FOUNDRY BUSINESS.
THAT'S REALLY SIGNIFICANT BECAUSE PAT GELSINGER, WHO TOOK
THE CEO ROLE BACK IN 2021, HAS REALLY PROMISED A TURNAROUND OF
THE COMPANY. PART OF THAT IS PROMISING TO
BUILD OUT THE FOUNDRY DIVISION AND START TO COMPETE WITH THE
LIKES OF TSMC. OF COURSE, THAT IS THE MOST
EXTREME, AS I SAID. SO PERHAPS MORE LIKELY RIGHT NOW
AS THEY TAKE A LESS EXTREME MOVE AND MAYBE HOLD OFF ON SOME
EXPENDITURE PLANS. THAT'S WHAT WE ARE HEARING FROM
SOURCES AT LEAST. WHAT DO YOU MAKE OF THE
TIMING OF THIS REPORTED MOVE? ANNABELLE: AS WE SAID, IT'S
REALLY AROUND, COMING VERY MUCH OFF THE BACK OF THOSE EARNINGS
ANNOUNCEMENTS AND REALLY POINTS TO THE AMOUNT OF PRESSURE THAT
PAT GELSINGER IS FACING HERE, GIVEN HE HAS STAKED SO MUCH ON
EFFORTS ON THIS MUCH-NEEDED TURNAROUND.
THE VARIOUS MOVES AND THE POTENTIAL FOR THESE TO BE
ENACTED, WELL, THE TIMING OF THOSE ALSO REALLY RELATES TO THE
UPCOMING MEETING THAT WE'VE GOT. THERE'S A BOARD MEETING THAT'S
TAKING PLACE IN SEPTEMBER, SO WHAT SOURCES HAVE TOLD US IS
THAT THOSE VARIOUS OPTIONS COULD BE PRESENTED AT THAT POINT IN
TIME. BUT NO DECISIONS APPEAR TO BE
IMMINENT FOR NOW, BUT CERTAINLY SOMETHING WE WILL BE TRACKING
VERY CLOSELY. PAUL: ALL RIGHT, BLOOMBERG TECH
REPORTER ANNABELLE DROULERS, THANK YOU SO MUCH FOR JOINING US
ON THE. INTEL SHARES ARE UP ABOUT 41% ON
YEAR. CHINESE EV MAKERS PERFORMING
PRETTY WELL IN CHINA AFTER SUFFERING A LITTLE BIT
YESTERDAY. WE DID SEE LI AUTO TRADING
SIGNIFICANTLY LOWER YESTERDAY BUT REBOUNDING STRONGER TODAY,
UP BY 8.8% NOW. SHARES CONNECTED TO CHINESE
VEHICLE MAKERS, ALSO DEALERS AS WELL, SHOWING THAT SOUND
REBOUND. WE'VE GOT SOME COMMENTARY FROM
ALL SPRING GLOBAL INVESTMENT SAYING THAT CELL DOWN IN CHINESE
EV MAKERS AFTER THE RESULTS WAS EXCESSIVE, SO WE ARE SEEING THE
MARKET RECOVERY NOW, DESPITE CHALLENGING OPERATING
ENVIRONMENT, DOWN OR PRESSURE ON SELLING PRICES, THESE EV MAKERS
ARE SHOWING THEY CAN PULL SEVERAL LEVERS THAT THEY CAN
RESORT TO. WE'VE GOTBYD, WHICH ACTUALLY HAD
A PRETTY DECENT SET OF NUMBERS YESTERDAY, BETTER BY 6%.
GREAT WALL MOTOR BETTER BY 8%. CHINESE INSURERS ARE ALSO AMONG
THE TOP GAINERS THAT WE ARE SEEING TODAY.
WE'VE GOT CHINA PACIFIC INSURANCE BETTER BY 6.8%.
A POSITIVE DAY ALL AROUND ON THE MAINLAND.
WE GOT THE CSI 300 BETTER BY, LET'S SEE NOW, ABOUT 1.6% AT THE
MOMENT. JUST A LITTLE BIT MORE ON THOSE
INSURANCE STOCKS FOR YOU. THOSE STRONG FIRST-HALF PROFITS
REALLY BOOSTING INVESTOR SENTIMENT HERE.
RESULTS GENERALLY STRONG ACROSS ALL PEERS, ACCORDING TO
BLOOMBERG INTELLIGENCE. WE HAVE MORE IN A MOMENT.
THIS IS BLOOMBERG. ♪
♪ PAUL: WELCOME BACK.
WE GOT CHINA MARKETS JUST HITTING LUNCH.
COULD BE A CELEBRATORY LUNCH. THE CSI 300 HAVING A BETTER DAY
-- A GOOD DAY. VERY STRONG VOLUMES AS WELL.
LOOKS LIKE ABOUT 60% HIGHER THAN THE AVERAGE VOLUME FOR THIS TIME
OF DAY. POSITIVE EARNINGS RELATED NEWS
AS WE WERE JUST DISCUSSING, PARTICULARLY OUT OF THE
INSURANCE SECTOR, HELPING TO BOOST SENTIMENT.
BANK OF CHINA SAYING IT'S GOING TO BE ANNOUNCING ITS FIRST
INTERIM DIVIDEND SINCE LISTING BACK IN 2006.
BROADER CONTEXT, THOUGH, 80% OF THE WAY INTO CHINA'S EARNINGS
SEASON. 60% OF CSI 300 STOCKS MISSING
ESTIMATES. CSI 300 BETTER BY ONE --
1.7%. AVRIL: WE ARE ABOUT 87% -- 80%
OF THE WAY INTO THE MSCI CHINA ON REPORTING.
AS YOU MENTIONED, WE HAVE ABOUT 60% OF THOSE COMPANIES MISSING
ON ESTIMATES. AND IT IS DISAPPOINTING RELATIVE
TO ESTIMATES, SO MORE MISSES THAN HITS.
THE THREE BEST SECTORS BASED ON AGGREGATE SURPRISE ARE UTILITIES
, COMMUNICATIONS SERVICES, CONSUMER DISCRETIONARY.
BUT TRAILING, THE ONES THAT ARE MISSING ARE THE CONSUMER
STAPLES, INFOTECH, AS WELL AS MATERIALS.
SOMETHING TO KEEP IN MIND AS WE TAKE STOCK OF THIS EARNINGS
SEASON, HOW WE'VE FARED SO FAR. LET'S TAKE A LOOK AT THIS NEXT
PAGE. EVEN AS WE TALK ABOUT THE MICRO
SIDE OF THINGS, WE ALSO WANTED TO KEEP AN EYE ON MACRO DATA
DROPPING IN JAPAN TODAY. AND WE GOT THE TOKYO CORE CPI
PRINT, IT WAS HOTTER THAN EXPECTED AND PICKED UP FROM THE
PRIOR MONTH, SO JUSTIFYING ANOTHER HIKE FROM THE BANK OF
JAPAN. CERTAINLY, PERHAPS CLOUDING THE
PICTURE A LITTLE AS SOME OF THESE OTHER DATA POINTS THAT WE
GOT. JOBLESS RATE TICKING HIGHER, AND
WE ALSO SAW A MISS ON INDUSTRIAL PRODUCTION AND RETAIL SALES, SO
NOT QUITE AS CLEAR-CUT. IF YOU FLIP THE PAGE AND TAKE A
LOOK AT WHAT WE SEE ON DOLLAR-YEN, IT'S INTERESTING TO
SEE HOW EVEN THOUGH WE GOT HOTTER THAN EXPECTED CPI NUMBERS
OUT OF TOKYO, WHICH IS OF COURSE THE NATIONWIDE INDICATOR,
LOOKING AT THE YEN, IT IS NOT THAT MUCH STRONGER, ACTUALLY
WEAKENING TODAY. IT JUST GIVES YOU A SENSE OF HOW
IMPORTANT THOSE FED EXPECTATIONS ARE GOING FORWARD FOR THE PAIR.
TO GET THE SENSE THAT THE YEN MIGHT NOT RALLY VERY MUCH MORE
UNLESS WE SEE A FURTHER DETERIORATION IN THE U.S.
ECONOMY. STAYING WITH JAPAN, THE NATION'S
SUPPORT FOR THE NATURAL GAS INDUSTRY HAS FUELED THE RAPID
EXPANSION OF THE $250 BILLION LNG MARKET OVER THE LAST
HALF-CENTURY. THE NATION HAS FEW GAS RESERVES
OF ITS OWN BUT HAS MADE ITSELF INDISPENSABLE AT EVERY LINK IN
THE SUPPLY CHAIN. OUR SENIOR ENERGY REPORTER HAS
MORE ON TODAY'S BIG TAKE. CAN YOU EXPLAIN TO US HOW KEY
JAPAN HAS BEEN TO THE LNG INDUSTRY?
THE LNG INDUSTRY WOULD NOT BE HERE TODAY IF IT WERE NOT FOR
JAPAN. I'VE SPOKEN TO PEOPLE FROM
BRUNEI TO AUSTRALIA TO THE UNITED STATES AND THEY ALL GAVE
ME THE SAME KIND OF MESSAGE, THAT IT WAS JAPANESE SUPPORT
FROM THE VERY BEGINNING THAT GOT THESE GIANT, LIQUEFIED NATURAL
GAS EXPORT FACILITIES OFF THE GROUND.
THEY COST TENS OF BILLIONS OF DOLLARS AND THEY NEED BUYERS.
THE JAPANESE WERE THE FIRST THERE IN QATAR, AND AUSTRALIA,
MALAYSIA, INDONESIA, EVEN JAPAN, EVEN THE UNITED STATES RIGHT
AFTER THE FUKUSHIMA DISASTER IN 2011, THEY WERE THERE WHEN THE
SHALE BOOM WAS HAPPENING. THEY ARE FINANCING IT WITH THEIR
BANKS. THE JAPANESE PUBLIC FINANC OR
JAY BAKER -- FINANCER J BANK IS THE LARGEST FINANCER IN THE
WORLD. YOU ALSO HAVE TECHNOLOGY
COMPANIES WHO HAVE BUILT THE MOST LNG PLANTS ANYWHERE IN THE
WORLD. THE JAPANESE KIND OF SPEARHEADED
THE INVENTION OF THE MODERN LNG VESSEL AND THEY OWN THE MOST LNG
VESSELS ON EARTH. AND THEY ARE ALSO THE BIGGEST
SUPPLIER OF NATURAL GAS FIRED TURBINES.
IF YOU WANT TO BUILD A NATURAL GAS POWER PLANT, YOU'RE LIKELY
GOING TO BE BUYING FROM A JAPANESE COMPANY.
ACROSS THE ENTIRE SUPPLY CHAIN, JAPAN PLAYS A VERY KEY ROLE.
DOMINANT PLAYERS. IS IT POSSIBLE TO QUANTIFY THE
EXTENT TO WHICH THEY PLAY THIS ROLE IN THE GLOBAL SUPPLY CHAIN?
FOR THIS STORY ON THE BLOOMBERG TERMINAL WEBSITE, WE
HAD AN EXCLUSIVE ANALYSIS THAT SHOWED THAT IN THE PREVIOUS
FISCAL YEAR, JAPANESE COMPANIES MADE $14 BILLION FROM GAS
RELATED BUSINESSES. PUT THAT INTO CONTEXT.
JAPAN'S TOP CONSUMER ELECTRONIC COMPANIES, I AM TALKING SONY AND
NINTENDO, MADE ABOUT THAT MUCH AS WELL IN PROFIT.
IT JUST SHOWS HOW LARGE JAPAN IS IN THAT SPACE.
AND IT IS BIG BUSINESS FOR THEM. EVEN THOUGH THEY ARE NOT
PRODUCING THE GUEST THEMSELVES, THEY ARE INVESTED IN PROJECTS --
THE GAS THEMSELVES, THEY ARE INVESTED IN PROJECTS, THEY ARE
FACILITATING THE TRADING OF GAS. WHEN IT GETS TO PORTS LIKE IN
THAILAND OR MEXICO, THEY ARE ALSO BEING BURNED IN FACILITIES
BUILT BY JAPANESE OR THAT HAVE PARTS FROM JAPANESE COMPANIES.
PAUL: WHAT DOES JAPAN'S SUPPORT OF GAS MEAN FOR GLOBAL CLIMATE
GOALS? THAT'S THE DIFFICULT
QUESTION. THERE HAVE BEEN
ENVIRONMENTALISTS THAT HAVE COME OUT AND SAID THAT JAPAN
SUPPORTING THE DEVELOPING OF NATURAL GAS MARKETS FROM
SOUTHEAST ASIA, WHERE THEY ARE SELLING THEIR TECHNOLOGY AND
SERVICES, RISKS THEM LATCHING ONTO GAS AND USING GAS FOR
DECADES AFTER THESE FACILITIES ARE BUILT INSTEAD OF QUICKLY
SHIFTING TO RENEWABLE ENERGY. JAPAN AND OTHERS WITHIN THE LNG
INDUSTRY ALREADY THAT GAS -- INDUSTRY ARGUE THAT GAS IS A
BRIDGE FUEL, A WAY FOR COUNTRIES TO REDUCE THEIR DEPENDENCE ON
COAL AND SHIFT TO GUEST, WHICH EMITS -- SHIFT TO GAS, WHICH
EMITS ABOUT HALF THE CO2. PERHAPS GAS IS NOT AS CLEAN AS
INITIALLY THOUGHT. METHANE EMISSIONS ARE A LARGE
PROBLEM IN THE NATURAL GAS SUPPLY CHAIN.
IT MAKES THE IMMEDIATE IMPACT CLIMATE IMPACT A LITTLE BIT
HARSHER THAN WHAT WAS INITIALLY THOUGHT.
ALTOGETHER, THERE IS THIS ARGUMENT THAT PERHAPS JAPAN'S
GAS EMPIRE DOES RISK GETTING THE WORLD USING MORE FOSSIL FUELS
FOR LONGER AND IT POTENTIALLY NOT HITTING AMBITIOUS CLIMATE
GOALS BY THE MIDDLE OF THE CENTURY.
PAUL: OF COURSE, JAPAN USED TO GENERATE A LOT OF ENERGY FROM
NUCLEAR POWER. IS WHAT WE ARE SEEING IN THE GAS
MARKET PERHAPS A REFLECTION OF NERVOUSNESS FOLLOWING THE
FUKUSHIMA NUCLEAR DISASTER? AND COULD IT BE PERHAPS THAT
IT'S TIME FOR JAPAN TO EXPLORE THESE OPTIONS AGAIN IN TERMS OF
NUCLEAR ENERGY? YEAH, I MEAN, CERTAINLY
JAPAN'S STRATEGY TO EXPAND GAS MARKETS ABROAD IS ONE, BECAUSE
THEY ARE NOT SURE WHERE THERE NATURAL GAS TO MENTAL GO.
AFTER THE FUKUSHIMA DISASTER -- GAS DEMAND WILL GO.
AFTER THE FUKUSHIMA DISASTER, THEY HAD 50 NUCLEAR REACTORS
THAT WERE SHUT. THEY'VE ONLY.
RESTARTED ABOUT A THIRD OF THOSE.
OTHERS HAVE BEEN DECOMMISSIONED. DEPENDING ON HOW MANY REACTORS
THEY RESTART, THEY MIGHT NOT NEED THIS GAS SO THEY CAN ON
SELLER TO OTHER MARKETS. CERTAINLY, GAS POSES A FEW RISKS
FOR JAPAN AS WELL ECONOMICALLY. IT'S EXPENSIVE.
THE NUCLEAR POWER PLANT THAT ARE IDLE AND JAPAN HAVE BEEN BUILT,
THEY ARE READY TO GO -- IDLE IN JAPAN HAVE BEEN BUILT, THEY ARE
READY TO GO. THEY CAN RESTART AND BEGIN
PRODUCING ELECTRICITY AT A MUCH CHEAPER RATE.
THE PROBLEM IS THERE HAVE BEEN MANY HURDLES.
THERE HAVE BEEN LOCAL HURDLES. THE REGULATORY HURDLES ARE STILL
QUITE HIGH. YOU HAVE TO DO A LOT OF
UPGRADES AND THE MANPOWER WITHIN JAPAN'S NUCLEAR REGULATOR IS
ALSO LIMITED SO THEY ARE NOT ABLE TO CHECK ALL THESE PLANTS
AND GET THEM ONLINE FAST ENOUGH. BUT CERTAINLY, THAT IS SOMETHING
THAT THE JAPANESE GOVERNMENT AND JAPANESE COPIES ARE ACUTELY
AWARE OF, THAT THEIR DEPENDENCE ON GAS AND ITS EXPENSIVE FUEL
DOES MEAN THAT NUCLEAR POSES A REALLY LARGE BENEFIT IF THEY CAN
GET THESE FACILITIES BACK ONLINE.
A BIT OF AN ENERGY CONUNDRUM. GREAT TO GET YOU IN SHARING
THEIR WORK FROM YOU AND THE TEAM ON THIS STORY.
REALLY INTERESTING STUFF, FASCINATING REALLY.
SENIOR ENERGY REPORTER STEPHEN STAPCZYNSKI.
I ENCOURAGE EVERYONE TO READ MORE ON THIS STORY IN TODAY'S
BIG TAKE. TERMINAL SUBSCRIBERS CAN READ
THE STORY. CHECK IT OUT ON BLOOMBERG.COM.
PAUL? PAUL: ALL RIGHT.
BILLIONAIRE MUKESH AMBANI HAS DOUBLED DOWN ON RELIANCE'S AI
AMBITIONS AND HIS SHAREHOLDERS ADDRESS ON THURSDAY.
DETAILS ON HIS PLANS FOR THE COMPANY, UP NEXT.
THIS IS BLOOMBERG. ♪
♪ WE HAVE BUILT AN AI-NATIVE
DIGITAL INFRASTRUCTURE FOR ALL RELIANCE BUSINESSES.
THIS ONGOING TECH DRIVEN TRANSFORMATION OF RELIANCE WILL
PROPEL YOUR COMPANY INTO A NEW ORBIT OF HYPER GROWTH AND
MULTIPLY ITS VALUE FOR YEARS TO COME.
PAUL: RELIANCE INDUSTRIES' CHAI RMAN MUKESH AMBANI DELIVERING
HIS ANNUAL SHAREHOLDERS ADDRESS. THIS GET MORE DETAILS ON HIS
AMBITIOUS PLANS FOR RELIANCE. THESE ADDRESSES ARE MUCH
ANTICIPATED, SIMILAR IN THE WAY THAT WARREN BUFFETT'S ANNUAL
SHAREHOLDER ADDRESSES OFTEN ARE. WHAT WERE THE KEY TAKEAWAYS?
THE ONE KEY TAKEAWAYS HERE, THE STREET WAS EXPECTING THAT HE
WOULD BE GIVING A TIMELINE FOR THE PROPOSED IP OF HIS TELECOM
VENTURE AND RETAIL VENTURE BUT HE DID NOT MENTION THAT.
HE JUST TOLD, THERE WERE AT LEAST THREE COMPANIES WHICH HAVE
GOT VALUATION OF 100 MILLION. THE MOST HIGHLIGTING FACTOR WAS
HE MENTIONED ABOUT ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE, AI, AT LEAST 18
TIMES, WHICH IS LIKE A CLEAR-CUT, YOUKNOW, TELLING HOW
A COMPANY, WHICH IS FROM A PR PLAY, O COMPANY, TRANSFORMING
WITH THE ELP OFA I. HE MENTIONED SEVERAL TIMES THAT
THE COMPANY IS GOING TO BE A DEEP TECH COMPANY.
IT'S NOT RESTRICTING AI TO ITS TELECOM VENTUREUT IT'S AL
GOING TO USE THAT AI FACILITY TO HEALTH CARE, RETAIL.
THE'S CLEAR-CUT MENTION, CLEAR-CUT PLANS MENTION HOW OIL
COMPANIES TRANSFORM INTO A DEEP TECH COMPANY USING AI.
HE ALSO MEIONED ABOT ESTBLISHING A GIGAWATT SCLE AI
READY DAT CENTER WHICH WILL MPEE WITH AMAZON'S.
HE CLARIFIED S INTETION. HE ALSO MADE IT SHAROLDERS
HAPPY BY GIVING A BONUS SHARE. JEFRIES HAVE- ITS PRICE
TARGET BECAUSE THERE WANO MENTION OF CAPITAL EXPENDITURE,
FURTHE TELECOM VENTURE OR RETAIL VETURE.
NET TO NET. SHEHOLDERS ARE VERY HAPP
BECAUE TH'VE GOT BONUS SHARE.
UT THEY RE NOT HPY BECAUSE THEY ULD NO GE A
TIMELINE FOR THE PROPOSED 'S FOR THE TELECOM VENTRE AN
RETAIL VENTURE. BUT E STREET IS LIKE ACUTELY
WATCHING HOW THIS COMANY IS GOING TO LEVERAG THE AI
CAPABILITY FORUSES. THEY WILL BE GETTING 100 GB OF
STORAGETO KE HEIRIDEO, ET
HE SAID THREE COMPANIES, AT LEAST THREE COANIESWILL BE,
THE VALATIO ISVER 100 BILLION.
HEID NOT MENTION MORE DETILS ABOUT T MERGER WITHNEY AND
IING H TING FORDI AD B K
FOS E
RE,MEESYNE >SEISNHOUT. H BA
I,UKO OBUI BOV EO'RIASSHE
LOIATEOIAE' WIIINTI.E WHNTIRME N
COFHIEI PPE T OMBEG.
♪ PAUL: ALL RIGHT, LET'S TAKE A
LOOK AT HOW MARKETS ARE TRACKING AROUND THE ASIA-PACIFIC, ZEROING
IN ON SOME OF CHINA'S BANKS. BANK OF POSITIVE TERRITORY TO
THE TUNE OF 0.8%. BANK OF CHINA ANNOUNCING ITS
FIRST INTERIM DIVIDEND SINCE LISTING WAY BACK IN 2006.
WE ARE HEARING THAT ALL CHINA'S MAJOR LENDERS SAY THEY ARE ALSO
CONSIDERING INTERIM DIVIDENDS. I WONDER IF THIS MIGHT HAVE ANY
IMPACT ON THAT DECISION. BLOOMBERG IS REPORTING THAT
CHINA IS CONSIDERING ALLOWING REFINANCING ON MORTGAGES CHEMO
TILL WE WORKED 5.4 -- CUMULATIVELY WORTH $5.4
TRILLION. TAKE A LOOK AT SHIP STOCKS AS
WELL. WE DID BRING IN THE NEWS THAT
INTEL IS REPORTED TO BE CONSIDERING SPLITTING OFF ITS
FOUNDRY BUSINESS AND PERHAPS SCRAPPING FACTORY PRODUCTION.
ASML'S CHIP BUSINESS MIGHT ALSO BE FACING NEW CURBS FROM THE
NETHERLANDS IN TERMS OF PROVIDING A COMMIT TO CHINA.
ALL RIGHT -- PROVIDING EQUIPMENT TO CHINA.
ALL RIGHT, THAT IS IT FOR "BLOOMBERG MARKETS: ASIA."
WE'VE GOT "HORIZONS: MIDDLE EAST AND AFRICA" COMING UP NEXT.